Finding Aid for Michelle Krebs papers, 1984-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michelle Krebs papers
1984-2009
Krebs, M. (Michelle)
2010125 Aa 2 Ac
Topical files and writings of Michelle Krebs, a Detroit-based freelance automotive writer who served as editorial coordinator and contributing editor for various publications of the automotive industry as well as contributing journalist for newspapers and general-interest magazines.
17 linear feet
3 oversize items
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was donated by Michelle Krebs (donor no. 10335 ) in 2010 and 2012.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michelle Krebs, a graduate of Syracuse University, is an authority on the automotive industry and, as a full-time freelance automotive journalist, writes regularly for numerous publications, such as the New York Times, the Detroit Free Press, Parade, Motor Trends, and Auto Week. She is an Adjunct Professor at Detroit's College for Creative Studies and served as president of the Automotive Press Association of Detroit. Ms. Krebs was the senior editor of Auto World, a monthly consumer magazine for car buyers, and the author of "Careers in the Auto Industry," which is included in a series that won the New York Public Library's award for best books for young people. She is the author of a syndicated automotive column, "Down the Road," which appears in numerous North American newspapers. At this writing (July 2010), Krebs was senior analyst and editor at large for Edmunds Auto Observer.
The Michelle Krebs collection includes her writings, in the form of newspaper and magazine clippings, as well as research materials collected as part of her professional work as analyst and journalist for the automotive industry. The papers are arranged in the following series: Writings, Topical Files, and Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications, and Miscellaneous Audio Visual Materials. The 2012 accession contains additions to the Topical Files, Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications series.
Subjects:
Automobile industry and trade.; Automobile industry and trade--Periodicals.; Women journalists.; Krebs, M. (Michelle)
Genre Terms:
Advertisements.; DVDs.; Compact discs.; Photographs.; Promotional materials.; Videotapes.
- Writings
  The Writings series includes magazine and newspaper articles written by Krebs and publications in which she served as editorial coordinator, as well as a copy of her book, "Cars," published in 1999 as part of the Careers without College series.
  - Auto Show, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Auto Test, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Auto Week, 1990-1999 (Box 1)
  - Auto World, 2000-2003; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Automotive Business International, 1999; 2000 (Box 1)
  - Automotive Hall of Fame, 1995; 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Automotive News, 1984-1998; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Automotive News International, 2000 (Box 1)
  - "Careers without College: Cars,", 1999 (Box 1)
  - Child, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Consumers Digest, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
  - Crain's Chicago Business, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Crain's Detroit Business, 1991-2006 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Detroit Free Press, 1997-2004 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Monthly, 1991; 1995 (Box 1)
  - Detroit News, 1991; 1993 (Box 1)
  - Diversion, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Family Money, 2000; 2001 (Box 1)
  - Inc., 1987-2005 (Box 1)
  - Medical Economics, 1999-2002 (Box 2)
  - Motor Matters: Down the Road, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Motor Trends, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - New Car Test Drive, 1995; 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - New York Times, 1992-2005; 9 folders (Box 2)
  - North American Auto Show "Show Talk,", 1993; 1998 (Box 2)
  - Parade, 1998-2002 (Box 2)
  - Popular Science, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Readers Digest, 2002 undated (Box 2)
  - Robb Report, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Selling Power, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Pilot, 1994; 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chronological files
    - 1984 (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1987, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
    - 1990 (Box 2)
    - 1991 (Box 2)
    - 1992 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series includes documentation collected by Krebs on various topics related to the automotive industry, such as automobile insurance, vehicle safety features, and alternative fuel sources.
  - American concept cars, 1988-1997 (Box 3)
  - Auctions, 1987-1993 (Box 3)
  - Automotive history (Box 3)
  - Components, 1990; 1998 (Box 3)
  - Education, 1993; undated (Box 3)
  - Exports, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Financing, 1985; 1993; 1994 (Box 3)
  - Future products, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Hybrid vehicles and alternative fuel, 1998; undated (Box 3)
  - Insurance and theft, 1989-1995 (Box 3)
  - Insurance policies, 1992-1995 (Box 3)
  - Japanese automobile market, 1990-1992; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Museums (Box 3)
  - Pricing, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Pollution prevention, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Racing, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Roadside assistance, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Sales, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications
  Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications includes brochures, photographs, slides, and press releases related to automobile shows, automobile companies, and suppliers of automotive components. In addition, there is an extensive collection of audiovisual materials promoting new car models and products during the period from 1981 to 2009.
  - Print
    - AAA, 1981-1995; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - AC Cars Limited, 1993-1995 (Box 4)
    - Acura, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - Alfa Romeo, 1990; 1995 (Box 4)
    - Allied Signal, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
    - American Iron and Steel Institute, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Aston Martin, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Audi, 1985-1995 (Box 4)
    - Axcessaustralia, 1998 (Box 4)
    - BMW, 1990-2003 (Box 4)
    - Bentley, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Bose, undated (Box 4)
    - Budd Company, 1992-1995 (Box 4)
    - Buick, 1992; 2008 (Box 4)
    - Cadillac, 2002-2003 (Box 4)
    - Cadillac, 1999 (Folder 1)
    - Chrysler, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Corvette, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Denso, 1998 (Box 4)
    - DuPont Automotive, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Economist Intelligence Unit, 1990-1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Eon, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Goodyear, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Holden Special Vehicles, 2002; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Honda, 1990-1996 (Box 5)
    - Hummer, 2004-2005 (Box 5)
    - Hyundai, 1991; 1997 (Box 5)
    - Infiniti, 1996; 2005 (Box 5)
    - Inland Fisher Guide, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Jaguar, 1985; 1990 (Box 5)
    - A.T. Kearny, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Kia, 1993-1996 (Box 5)
    - Land Rover, 1988-1991 (Box 5)
    - Learjet, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Lexus, 1990; 2005 (Box 5)
    - Lotus, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    - Mascotech Trends, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
    - Mazda, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
    - Mercedes, 1985-1988 (Box 5)
    - Mercedes, 2002-2003 (Folder 1)
    - Meritor, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Motor Vehicle Manufacturers Association, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
    - North American International Auto Show, 1995-2008 (Box 5)
    - Polk, 1990-1995 (Box 5)
    - Porsche, 1985-1991 (Box 5)
    - J.D. Power, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Runzheimer, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    - SMC Automotive Alliance, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Saab, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
    - Saturn, 1985-1992; 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Siemens, 1998 (Box 6)
    - TRW, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Toyota, 1984-1995 (Box 6)
    - Visteon (Ford Motor Company), 1998 (Box 6)
    - Volkswagen, 1991; 2004 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Audio/visual, primarily DVDs, CDs, CD-ROMs, with some VHS videotapes, circa 2003-2007
    - Acura (Box 6)
    - Aston Martin (Box 6)
    - Audi (Box 7)
    - BMW (Box 7)
    - Buick (Box 7)
    - Cadillac, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Chevrolet (Box 7)
    - Chrysler (Box 7)
    - Citroen (Box 7)
    - Dodge (Box 7)
    - Ford (Box 7)
    - GM / GMC, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Honda (Box 7)
    - Hummer (Box 8)
    - Hyundai (Box 8)
    - Infiniti (Box 8)
    - Isuzu (Box 8)
    - Jaguar (Box 8)
    - Jeep (Box 8)
    - Kia (Box 8)
    - Land Rover (Box 8)
    - Lexus (Box 8)
    - Lincoln Mercury (Box 8)
    - Maserati (Box 8)
    - Mazda (Box 8)
    - Mercedes (Box 8)
    - Mitsubishi (Box 8)
    - Nissan (Box 8)
    - Oldsmobile (Box 8)
    - Opel (Box 8)
    - Pontiac (Box 8)
    - Porsche (Box 8)
    - Renault (Box 8)
    - Rolls Royce (Box 9)
    - Saab (Box 9)
    - Saturn (Box 9)
    - Scion (Box 9)
    - Subaru (Box 9)
    - Suzuki (Box 9)
    - Toyota (Box 9)
    - Volkswagen (Box 9)
    - Volvo (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Auto components (Box 9)
      - Auto manufacturers (Box 9)
- Miscellaneous Audio/Visual Materials, CD-ROMs, VHS videotapes, DVDs
  Miscellaneous Audio Visual Materials includes electronic copies of Ms. Krebs' documents and cassette tapes and CDs of her appearances on "The Auto Lab" an automotive broadcast series about the automotive industry, its history, and its culture.
  - Auto shows, 2004-2009 (Box 9)
  - Krebs documents (Box 9)
  - Presentations, 2003; 2004; 2009 (Box 9)
  - "The Auto Lab: a broadcast service of Automotive Technology,", 1997-2008 (scattered); 41 audiocassettes; 5 optical disks CDs (Box 10)
- Accession, 2011
  - Topical files
    - Advertising (Box 11)
    - Design (Box 11)
    - Driving (Box 11)
    - Electric Drive Transportation Association (Box 11)
    - Environment (Box 11)
    - Fuel Alternatives (Box 11)
    - Fuel Cell Power (Box 11)
    - ITS, Institute of Transportation Studies (Box 11)
    - Lorraine (Box 11)
    - Lorraine, Apeilor (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Museum
      - Automobile, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Behring Automotive Museum (Box 11)
      - Blackhawk (Box 11)
      - Chrysler, Walter P. (Box 11)
      - Henry Ford (Box 11)
      - National Corvette, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Safety, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Sales (Box 11)
    - Super-Clean Cars (Box 11)
    - Sustainable Development (Box 11)
    - Technology (Box 11)
    - Universal Studios (Box 11)
  - Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications
    - Print
      - 3M (Box 12)
      - AC Delco (Box 12)
      - Acura, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Aero, Let's Go (Box 12)
      - Air Products (Box 12)
      - Amerigon (Box 12)
      - Anuvu Fuel Cell Products (Box 12)
      - Aston Martin (Box 12)
      - Audi, 4 folders (Box 12)
      - Bentley (Box 12)
      - Ballard Power Systems (Box 12)
      - Bertone (Box 12)
      - Bertone-SKF Filo (Folder Ac)
      - Bosch, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Bridgestone/Firestone, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - BMW, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Buick (Box 12)
  - Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications (cont.)
    - Print (cont.)
      - California Fuel Cell Partnership (Box 12)
      - Cadillac (Box 12)
      - Chevrolet, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Chevrolet, 5 folders (Box 13)
      - Chrysler, 4 folders (Box 13)
      - Continental Teves (Box 13)
      - Daimler Benz, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Daimler Chrysler, 8 folders (Box 13)
      - Delphi (Box 13)
      - Dodge, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Dupont (Box 13)
      - Energy Conversion Devices (Box 13)
      - Ferrari (Box 13)
      - Ford, General, 4 folders (Box 13)
      - Ford (Box 14)
        - General, 12 folders (Box 14)
        - Aviation (Box 14)
        - Clippings, 4 folders (Box 14)
        - Credit (Box 14)
        - Escape (Box 14)
        - F-150, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Fordism (Box 14)
        - Freestar (Box 14)
        - GT (Box 14)
        - Legend (Box 14)
        - Mustang, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Thunderbird, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - ZF Joint Venture (Box 14)
      - Fusion (Box 14)
      - General Motors, 5 folders (Box 15)
      - General Motors Corporation (Box 15)
      - Giugiaro (Box 15)
      - HitchCam (Box 15)
      - Honda, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Hummer (Box 15)
      - Hyundai, 6 folders (Box 15)
      - Infiniti, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Isuzu (Box 15)
      - Jaguar, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Jeep (Box 15)
      - Kia, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Land Rover (Box 15)
  - Promotional Materials, Press Releases, and Publications (cont.)
    - Print (cont.)
      - Lexus, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Lincoln, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Lund Truck Accessories (Box 15)
      - Maserati (Box 15)
      - Maybach, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Mazda, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Mercedes-Benz, 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Mercury, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Michelin
        - General (Box 16)
        - Bibendum, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Mitsubishi (Box 16)
      - Model E Corporation (Box 16)
      - Nissan, 6 folders (Box 16)
      - Pininfarina (Box 16)
      - PNI (Box 16)
      - Pontiac, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Porsche (Box 16)
      - Rolls Royce, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Rostra Precision Controls (Box 16)
      - Saab, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Saturn (Box 16)
      - SEMA (Box 16)
      - Siemens VDO Automotive (Box 16)
      - SKF (Box 16)
      - Stuart Energy (Box 16)
      - Subaru, 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Suzuki, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - TI Automotive (Box 16)
      - Toyota (Box 17)
        - General, 5 folders (Box 17)
        - Scion (Box 17)
      - RW Automotive (Box 17)
      - Vanceva (Box 17)
      - Visteon (Box 17)
      - VizuaLogic (Box 17)
      - Volkswagon (Box 17)
      - Volvo, 2 folders (Box 17)
Related Material
Michelle Krebs' collection of books about the automobile industry have been separately cataloged and placed in the library's printed collection.